These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2025-08 were created by ZoowlCZ.
ⓘ Very special thanks to Gwaith-i-Phethdain, Magpie of A Magpie's Nest and Friends, and Monoverantus
for their extraordinary work on deciphering the dialogs and lyrics.
ⓘ Special thanks also to TheGloriousLori and José Figueredo.
ⓘ For correct displaying of these subtitles, use a media player
supporting ASS tags in .srt files.
[Sindarin] I amar prestar aen.
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne nen.
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne chae.
[Sindarin] A han noston ned 'wilith.
[Sindarin] Tangado haid!
[English] Hold positions!
[Sindarin] Leithio i philinn!
[English] Release the arrows!
[Black Speech] Gûm-ishi...
[English] In the void...
[Black Speech] ...ashi...
[English] ...only...
[Black Speech] ...gurum!
[English] ...death!
[Sindarin] Im Arwen, Telin le thaed.
[English] I Arwen, I come to help you.
[Sindarin] Lasto beth nîn, tolo dan nan galad.
[English] Listen to my word, come back to the light.
[Sindarin] Dartho guin Beriain. Rych le ad tolthathon.
[English] Stay with the Hobbits. I will send horses for you.
[Sindarin] Hon mabathon! Rochon ellint im.
[English] I will take him! I am the swifter rider.
[Sindarin] Andelu i ven.
[English] The road is too dangerous.
[Sindarin] Frodo fîr. Ae athradon i hîr ...
[English] Frodo is dying. If I cross the river ...
[Sindarin] ... tûr gwaith nîn beriatha hon.
[English] ... the power of my people will protect him.
[Sindarin] Be iest lîn.
[English] As you wish.
[Sindarin] Noro lim Asfaloth, noro lim!
[English] Ride fast Asfaloth, ride fast!
[Sindarin] Noro lim Asfaloth!
[English] Ride fast Asfaloth!
[Sindarin] Nîn o Chithaeglir, lasto beth daer!
[English] Waters of the Misty Mountains, listen to the great word!
[Sindarin] Rimmo nîn Bruinen dan in Ulaer!
[English] Flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths!
[Sindarin] Nîn o Chithaeglir, lasto beth daer!
[English] Waters of the Misty Mountains, listen to the great word!
[Sindarin] Rimmo nîn Bruinen dan in Ulaer!
[English] Flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths!
[Sindarin] Lasto beth nîn. Tolo dan nan galad.
[English] Hear my voice. Come back to the light.
[Sindarin] A si i-Dhúath ú-orthor, Aragorn.
[English] The shadow does not hold sway yet, Aragorn.
[Sindarin] Ú or le a ú or nin.
[English] Not over you, not over me.
[Sindarin] Renich i lú i erui govannem?
[English] Do you remember when we first met?
[Sindarin] Nauthannen i ned ôl reniannen.
[English] I thought I had strayed into a dream.
[Sindarin] Gwenwin in enninath.
[English] Long years have passed.
[Sindarin] Ú-'arnech in naeth i si celich.
[English] You did not wear the troubles you carry now.
[Sindarin] Renich i beth i pennen?
[English] Do you remember what I told you?
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Sherkuk-ishi
[English] In your blood
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Shre nazg golugranu kilmi-nudu...
[English] Three Rings for the Elven-kings under the sky...
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul...
[English] ...One ring to find them...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Ombi kuzd-durbagu... shirku
[English] Seven for the Dwarf-lords... blood
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg thrakatulûk...
[English] ...One ring to bring them all...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Ash Burz-Durbagu burzum-ishi...
[English] One for the Dark lord on his dark throne...
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Agh burzum-ishi krimpatul.
[English] ...and in the darkness bind them.
[Sindarin] Havo dad, Legolas.
[English] Sit down, Legolas.
[Black Speech] Daghburz-ishi makha, ghurarmu shirku.
[English] In the land of Mordor, a sacrifice of blood.
[Black Speech] Makha gulshu darulu.
[English] Where the Shadows lie.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Sindarin] Anirne hene beriad i chên lîn.
[English] She wanted to protect her child.
[Sindarin] Ned Imladris nauthant e le beriathar aen.
[English] She thought in Rivendell you would be safe.
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Sindarin] Losto Caradhras, Sedho! Hodo!
[English] Sleep Redhorn, Be still! Lie Still!
[Sindarin] Nuitho i 'Ruith!
[English] Hold your Wrath!
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Quenya] Nai yarvaxëa rasselya...
[English] May your bloodstained horn...
[Quenya] ...taltuva ñotto-carinnar!
[English] ...fall upon enemy heads!
[Sindarin] Annon Edhellen edro hi ammen!
[English] Gate of the elves, open now for me!
[Sindarin] Fennas Nogothrim, lasto beth lammen.
[English] Doorway of the Dwarf-folk, listen to the word of my tongue.
[Quenya] Ando Eldarinwa...
[English] Gate of elves...
[Quenya] ...a lasta quettanya...
[English] ...listen to my word...
[Quenya] ...fenda casarinwa!
[English] ...threshold of dwarves!
[Sindarin] Mellon.
[English] Friend.
[Sindarin] Mae govannen, Legolas Thranduilion.
[English] Welcome, Legolas son of Thranduil.
[Sindarin] Govannas vîn gwennen le, Haldir o Lórien.
[English] Our fellowship stands in your debt, Haldir of Lórien.
[Sindarin] A Aragorn in Dúnedain...
[English] Oh, Aragorn of the Dúnedain...
[Sindarin] ...istannen le ammen.
[English] ...you are known to us.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen veriad lîn. Andelu i ven!
[English] We need your protection. The road is too dangerous!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen i dulu lîn!
[English] We need your support!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Andelu i ven!
[English] The road is too dangerous!
[Sindarin] Le aphadar aen.
[English] You are being tracked.
[Sindarin] Am meleth dîn...
[English] For her love...
[Sindarin] ...I ant e guil Arwen Undómiel pígatha.
[English] ...the gift of life of Arwen will fade.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e broniatha...
[English] I wish that she endures...
[Sindarin] ...Ad ae periatham athar i methid en-amar hen.
[English] ...even if we separate beyond the limits of this world.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e círatha na Valinor.
[English] I wish that she sails to Valinor.
[Quenya] Namárië.
[English] Farewell.
[Sindarin] Nadath nâ i moe cerich...
[English] There is much you have yet to do...
[Sindarin] ...dan...
[English] ...but...
[Sindarin] ...ú-'eveditham, Elessar.
[English] ...we shall not meet again, Elessar.
[Black Speech] Akha...
[English] Here...
[Black Speech] ...ashi...
[English] ...only...
[Black Speech] ...gurum!
[English] ...death!